In this clip, we'll talk about your first consultation with a plastic surgeon for breast reduction.
When you come in to see the plastic surgeon, it will be very important that you give all of your health history.
And, then the surgeon will perform a thorough physical examination and have a discussion with you about his findings and his recommendations for your breast reduction surgery.
During the examination, he will examine your breasts by palpation feeling the breast to make sure that there are no abnormalities.
No problems with the skin, no problems with the nipples, no problems with abnormal lumps or bumps or infections.
That the breasts have an appearance that would justify breast reduction.
Meaning, overly large for the body.
Usually, in the very very full C, D or higher cup range that they would be projecting below the fold of the breast.
So, therefore warranting the reduction.
And, then checking for such things as the symmetry of the breasts.
Do the two breasts match up or not?
In fact, most women do not have symmetric breasts.
And, most humans do not have two symmetric breasts.
So, this is a very common finding.
And, it's important for the person or patient to understand and the surgeon to understand as far as planning and results.